{
  "content": {
    "title": "Implementation of Different Network Topologies",
    "section": "Post-Test",
    "questions": [
      {
        "id": "q1",
        "question": "If one link fails, only that link is affected. All other links remain active. Which topology is this?",
        "options": [
          "a. Mesh Topology",
          "b. Star Topology",
          "c. Bus Topology",
          "d. Physical Topology"
        ],
        "answer": "b"
      },
      {
        "id": "q2",
        "question": "The Network Topology that supports bi-directional links between each possible node.",
        "options": [
          "a. Ring",
          "b. Mesh",
          "c. Star",
          "d. Tree"
        ],
        "answer": "b"
      },
      {
        "id": "q3",
        "question": "What are the advantages of hybrid topology?",
        "options": [
          "a. Scalable",
          "b. Flexible networking topology",
          "c. Highly efficient",
          "d. All of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "d"
      },
      {
        "id": "q4",
        "question": "In which topology, if the computer cable is broken, the network goes down?",
        "options": [
          "a. Irregular",
          "b. Ring",
          "c. Bus",
          "d. Star"
        ],
        "answer": "c"
      },
      {
        "id": "q5",
        "question": "For large networks which topology is generally used?",
        "options": [
          "a. Bus",
          "b. Ring",
          "c. Irregular",
          "d. Star"
        ],
        "answer": "d"
      },
      {
        "id": "q6",
        "question": "Terminators are used in which topology?",
        "options": [
          "a. Ring",
          "b. Bus",
          "c. Irregular",
          "d. Star"
        ],
        "answer": "b"
      },
      {
        "id": "q7",
        "question": "What is the central device in star topology?",
        "options": [
          "a. Hub",
          "b. Switch",
          "c. Both a and b",
          "d. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "c"
      },
      {
        "id": "q8",
        "question": "The data in ring topology moves in _______________ direction.",
        "options": [
          "a. One",
          "b. Two",
          "c. Four",
          "d. Doesnâ€™t move"
        ],
        "answer": "a"
      },
      {
        "id": "q9",
        "question": "The topology with highest reliability is:",
        "options": [
          "a. Bus topology",
          "b. Star topology",
          "c. Ring topology",
          "d. Mesh topology"
        ],
        "answer": "d"
      },
      {
        "id": "q10",
        "question": "Repeater are used in _______________.",
        "options": [
          "a. Mesh Topology",
          "b. Star Topology",
          "c. Bus Topology",
          "d. Ring Topology"
        ],
        "answer": "d"
      }
    ]
  }
}

